<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Reading Test 8 Section 1 - The pressure on Junior Doctors - Short Answer Question Type -->
<rss xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/" version="2.0">
<channel>
	<title>IELTStestONLINE</title>
	<link>https://www.ieltstestonline.com</link>
	<description>Online IELTS preparation</description>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-NZ</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>https://www.ieltstestonline.com</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>https://www.ieltstestonline.com</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[impact]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[impact@ieltstestonline.com]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[impact]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Patrick]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Bourne]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<generator>IELTS Test XML Creator</generator>

	<item>
		<title><![CDATA[Reading 8 section 1]]></title>
		<link>https://www.ieltstestonline.com/ielts-quiz/reading-8-section-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[impact]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ieltstestonline.com/?post_type=ielts_quiz&amp;p=9000016</guid>
		<description/>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The pressure on Junior Doctors</strong></p>

<p>In comparison with the lives of other postgraduate students, the life of a student doctor is far from easy. Despite the heavy workload, it seems that the more you learn, the more you realise what you still need to study, meaning that it becomes increasingly complex and difficult as the course progresses. As a result, it is not unusual for students to drop out. Misguided teachers attempt to simplify matters, but this can then result in incomplete understanding in an environment that demands the very best of its practitioners, and this can cause the situation.</p>

<p>The situation is little better in the year or two years after qualifying. Poorly paid for such long hours, many junior doctors find themselves becoming disillusioned with medicine. The more depressed they become, the more likely they are to look elsewhere for a career, wasting up to seven years of training and education. An unfortunate statistic is that of those that qualify as doctors, 18% do not remain in the profession for more than three years.</p>

<p>The problem can be more clearly defined by considering specific examples. In New Zealand and Britain, for example, the exodus of medical graduates is leaving the remaining newly qualified doctors with responsibilities that are beyond their capacity. In statistics from 1998 over half the graduates from one medical school in New Zealand left the country immediately after qualifying, and hospitals are really beginning to feel the shortage. Certain hospitals in Auckland, for example, do not have enough staff to cover the timetable, and some of the newly qualified doctors are finding themselves on call for 48 hours straight. In Britain, the situation is equally bleak.</p>

<p>The structure of the health service itself is the most important factor to be taken into account when considering the number of migrating British medical graduates. Junior doctors are required to take mentors, more senior doctors (often consultants), to act as supervisors. They are entrusted with the educational supervision of doctors in their first year of practice and are responsible for ensuring the application of the principles of good medical practice. However, when interviewed, slightly less than 60% of junior doctors had any positive feedback on the relationship. The remaining respondents described situations in which a consultant was accused of making unreasonable demands, bullying, being unfair, or being sexist. In more extreme cases, the consultant was portrayed as incompetent, insensitive or negligent towards patients.</p>

<p>A healthy mentoring relationship is likely to provide the mental and moral challenges essential to continuing self-improvement. But such statistics may encourage junior doctors to conclude that role models may not be a dependable way to impart professional values, attitudes and behaviour. Indeed, a survey of just under 200 nearly qualified doctors highlights significant gaps in their knowledge and understanding of basic care. It was found that many junior doctors do not know the signs indicating a patient is critically ill, a third of respondents failed to answer a question on how to deal with someone who was unconscious and none of the trainees identified all of the steps involved in using an oxygen mask.</p>

<p>In New Zealand, the situation, although having essentially the same effect of fewer junior doctors, has different causes. There are two main factors which explain this mass migration of medical graduates from New Zealand. The first factor is the student loans system where a medical graduate can leave university having accumulated a loan of anything up to NZ$60 000 in the course of training. By leaving the country, such graduates have the option of at least delaying the repayment of those loans. The other reason is the long hours. The stories of working hours a week being almost in the three-figure mark are often not exaggerated, and this is a situation which is worsening the fewer junior doctors there are.</p>

<p>In New Zealand, at least, a solution is being sought at a student level. The New Zealand Medical Students Association (NZMSA) is a national body that aims to advance the long-term interests of medical students and act as their advocate on a political level. Composed of students elected from the Otago and Auckland Medical Schools, the NZMSA aims to find a balance between the demands of the profession and the expectations of junior doctors. At a recent conference, the Association concluded that increasing student numbers or attracting overseas doctors is too short term to be successful and the roots of the problem need to be addressed, specifically in the area of student debt. Either way, there is no doubt that a solution is needed and needed quickly, not just in Britain and New Zealand, but in most countries.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>9000016</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2025-12-26 20:00:00]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2025-12-26 20:00:00]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:post_modified><![CDATA[2025-12-26 20:00:00]]></wp:post_modified>
		<wp:post_modified_gmt><![CDATA[2025-12-26 20:00:00]]></wp:post_modified_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[reading-8-section-1]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[ielts_quiz]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_ielts_cm_questions]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:17:{i:0;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:255:"<strong>Questions 1-11</strong><br><br>Do the following statements agree with the views of the writer?<br><br>Write:<br>YES if the statement agrees with the writer<br>NO if the statement does not agree with the writer<br>NOT GIVEN if the information is not given in the passage.";s:8:"question";s:66:"Medical courses are as difficult as any other postgraduate course.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:121:"Please provide an answer. Consider whether the passage states that medical courses are harder than other postgraduate courses.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:138:"Correct! The passage states medical students' lives are 'far from easy' compared to other postgraduate students, meaning it's more difficult.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:91:"The passage states that in comparison with other postgraduate students, it's 'far from easy'.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:138:"Correct! The passage states medical students' lives are 'far from easy' compared to other postgraduate students, meaning it's more difficult.";}i:1;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:61:"For student doctors, the course becomes easier the more you learn.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:106:"Please provide an answer. Consider what the passage says about learning more in medical school over time.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:130:"Correct! The passage states 'the more you learn, the more you realise what you still need to study', making it increasingly difficult.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:88:"The passage says 'the more you learn', the course becomes 'increasingly complex and difficult'.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:130:"Correct! The passage states 'the more you learn, the more you realise what you still need to study', making it increasingly difficult.";}i:2;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:42:"A number of students do not complete the course.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:101:"Please provide an answer. Consider whether the passage mentions students dropping out of the course.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:87:"Correct! The passage explicitly states 'it is not unusual for students to drop out'.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:73:"The passage clearly states 'it is not unusual for students to drop out'.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:3:"YES";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:87:"Correct! The passage explicitly states 'it is not unusual for students to drop out'.";}i:3;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:46:"Better teachers know how to simplify the course.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:110:"Please provide an answer. Consider what the passage says about teachers who attempt to simplify the material.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:135:"Correct! The passage refers to 'Misguided teachers' who attempt to simplify, suggesting this approach is incorrect, not better practice.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:116:"The passage calls teachers who attempt to simplify matters 'misguided', leading to 'incomplete understanding'.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:135:"Correct! The passage refers to 'Misguided teachers' who attempt to simplify, suggesting this approach is incorrect, not better practice.";}i:4;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:64:"Once qualified, the situation for junior doctors slightly improves.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:106:"Please provide an answer. Consider what the passage says about the situation after qualification.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:96:"Correct! The passage states 'The situation is little better' after qualifying, meaning it improves slightly.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:87:"The passage says 'The situation is little better in the year or two years after qualifying'.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:3:"YES";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:96:"Correct! The passage states 'The situation is little better' after qualifying, meaning it improves slightly.";}i:5;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:23:"Junior doctors are poor.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:116:"Please provide an answer. Consider whether the passage directly states that junior doctors are poor.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:156:"Correct! The passage states they are 'poorly paid for such long hours', but doesn't state whether they are actually poor. This information is not given.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:139:"While the passage says they are 'poorly paid', it doesn't state they are 'poor'. Being poorly paid doesn't necessarily mean being poor.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:9:"NOT GIVEN";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:156:"Correct! The passage states they are 'poorly paid for such long hours', but doesn't state whether they are actually poor. This information is not given.";}i:6;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:58:"Disillusioned doctors often move to another hospital to work.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:105:"Please provide an answer. Consider what the passage says disillusioned doctors do.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:152:"Correct! The passage states disillusioned doctors 'look elsewhere for a career, wasting up to seven years of training' - they quit medicine, not just change hospitals.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:154:"The text states that disillusioned doctors 'look elsewhere for a career, wasting up to seven years of training and education' - they didn't move to another hospital, they quit the medical practice.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:152:"Correct! The passage states disillusioned doctors 'look elsewhere for a career, wasting up to seven years of training' - they quit medicine, not just change hospitals.";}i:7;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:65:"The majority of students had nothing positive to say about their mentors.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:108:"Please provide an answer. Consider what percentage had positive feedback about mentors.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:155:"Correct! The passage states 'slightly less than 60% of junior doctors had any positive feedback', meaning just under 60% had something positive to say - not a majority saying nothing positive.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:144:"'Slightly less than 60% of junior doctors had any positive feedback on the relationship' - this means the majority (just under 60%) HAD positive feedback.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:155:"Correct! The passage states 'slightly less than 60% of junior doctors had any positive feedback', meaning just under 60% had something positive to say - not a majority saying nothing positive.";}i:8;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:76:"The root of the problem in New Zealand and Britain is essentially the same.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:117:"Please provide an answer. Consider whether the passage states the problems have the same or different causes.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:162:"Correct! The passage explicitly states: 'In New Zealand, the situation, although having essentially the same effect of fewer junior doctors, has different causes.'";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:163:"The passage states: 'In New Zealand, the situation, although having essentially the same effect of fewer junior doctors, has different causes.'";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:162:"Correct! The passage explicitly states: 'In New Zealand, the situation, although having essentially the same effect of fewer junior doctors, has different causes.'";}i:9;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:58:"Many junior doctors are unable to repay their student loans.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:114:"Please provide an answer. Consider whether the passage states doctors are unable to repay loans.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:165:"Correct! The passage mentions doctors can delay repayment by leaving the country, but doesn't state they are unable to repay. This information is not given.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:173:"The text refers to how junior doctors often leave the country to delay repaying their loans, but there is no reference to them being unable to pay them.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:9:"NOT GIVEN";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:165:"Correct! The passage mentions doctors can delay repayment by leaving the country, but doesn't state they are unable to repay. This information is not given.";}i:10;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:73:"The NZMSA has found a balance between expectation and reality.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:98:"Please provide an answer. Consider the verb tense in the passage about the NZMSA's aims.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:178:"Correct! The passage says the NZMSA 'aims to' find a balance (future intention), not that it 'has found' (past completion). The question uses past tense, which is not true.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:199:"The key is in the language used. If the NZMSA 'aims to' find a balance, this refers to the future, but the grammar of the question is 'has found' which suggests this was completed in the past, which therefore is not true.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:2:"NO";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:178:"Correct! The passage says the NZMSA 'aims to' find a balance (future intention), not that it 'has found' (past completion). The question uses past tense, which is not true.";}i:11;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:214:"<strong>Questions 12-14</strong><br><br>Complete the following text using <strong>NO MORE THAN TWO WORDS</strong> from the text.<br><br>A significant number of graduates from New Zealand and Britain are not remaining in the medical field. Poor relationships with (12) ________, student loan repayments and increasingly long (13) ________ are all contributory factors. The NZMSA is attempting to find an answer to the problem, but is wary of supporting ideas it perceives to be only (14) ________ solutions.";s:8:"question";s:67:"Poor relationships with (12) ________.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:97:"Please provide an answer. Look for who junior doctors have poor relationships with.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:125:"Correct! The passage discusses poor relationships with 'mentors' (senior doctors/consultants who supervise junior doctors).";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:106:"The passage refers to poor mentoring relationships and consultants making unreasonable demands.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:39:"MENTORS|THEIR MENTORS|MENTOR|THEIR MENTOR";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:125:"Correct! The passage discusses poor relationships with 'mentors' (senior doctors/consultants who supervise junior doctors).";}i:12;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:44:"increasingly long (13) ________.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:88:"Please provide an answer. Look for what is increasingly long that affects junior doctors.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:112:"Correct! The passage refers to 'long hours' and 'working hours a week being almost in the three-figure mark'.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:88:"The passage discusses 'the long hours' and 'working hours' as a contributory factor.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:19:"HOURS|WORKING HOURS";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:112:"Correct! The passage refers to 'long hours' and 'working hours a week being almost in the three-figure mark'.";}i:13;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:63:"it perceives to be only (14) ________ solutions.";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:91:"Please provide an answer. Look for what type of solutions the NZMSA is wary of.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:152:"Correct! The passage states the NZMSA concluded that 'increasing student numbers or attracting overseas doctors is too short term to be successful'.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:110:"The NZMSA is 'wary of supporting ideas it perceives to be' only 'short term' (or short-term) solutions.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:20:"SHORT-TERM|SHORT TERM";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:152:"Correct! The passage states the NZMSA concluded that 'increasing student numbers or attracting overseas doctors is too short term to be successful'.";}i:14;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:116:"<strong>Questions 15-17</strong><br><br>Answer the following questions using <strong>NO MORE THAN TWO WORDS OR A NUMBER</strong>.";s:8:"question";s:105:"In which year did over 50% of newly qualified doctors from a medical school in New Zealand leave the country?";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:78:"Please provide an answer. Look for a specific year mentioned in the passage.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:132:"Correct! The passage states: 'In statistics from 1998 over half the graduates from one medical school in New Zealand left the country'.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:93:"The passage mentions 'In statistics from 1998' when discussing this exodus of medical graduates.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:12:"IN 1998|1998";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:132:"Correct! The passage states: 'In statistics from 1998 over half the graduates from one medical school in New Zealand left the country'.";}i:15;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:40:"How are members of the NZMSA chosen?";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:85:"Please provide an answer. Look for how NZMSA members are selected.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:108:"Correct! The passage states the NZMSA is 'Composed of students elected from the Otago and Auckland Medical Schools'.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:78:"The NZMSA is 'Composed of students elected from' the medical schools.";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:40:"ELECTED|ELECTIONS|BY ELECTIONS|BY ELECTION";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:108:"Correct! The passage states the NZMSA is 'Composed of students elected from the Otago and Auckland Medical Schools'.";}i:16;a:10:{s:4:"type";s:12:"shortanswers";s:12:"instructions";s:0:"";s:8:"question";s:37:"Where are two-day shifts not uncommon?";s:6:"points";i:1;s:18:"no_answer_feedback";s:88:"Please provide an answer. Look for where doctors work 48-hour (2-day) shifts.";s:16:"correct_feedback";s:142:"Correct! The passage states: 'Certain hospitals in Auckland, for example...some of the newly qualified doctors are finding themselves on call for 48 hours straight'.";s:18:"incorrect_feedback";s:116:"The passage mentions 'Certain hospitals in Auckland' where doctors find themselves 'on call for 48 hours straight' (2 days).";s:15:"reading_text_id";i:0;s:14:"correct_answer";s:18:"AUCKLAND|IN AUCKLAND";s:15:"answer_feedback";s:142:"Correct! The passage states: 'Certain hospitals in Auckland, for example...some of the newly qualified doctors are finding themselves on call for 48 hours straight'.";}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
